<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Hello World!</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Hello World!</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Daily Logs for Devs: The 5-Minute Habit That Can 10x Your Output</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/05-21-25-daily-logging/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/05-21-25-daily-logging/</guid>
            <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-im-recommending-daily-logs-to-every-developer-i-work-with&#34;&gt;Why I&amp;rsquo;m Recommending Daily Logs to Every Developer I Work With&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most developers think productivity comes from better tooling, tighter sprint planning, or cutting meetings. Those help—but they don&amp;rsquo;t solve the &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; problem:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’re losing your own context, day after day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start-of-day brain fog, half-solved bugs, forgotten edge cases… they all point to one thing: you didn’t close the loop yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s why I advise every dev I coach or lead to adopt a &lt;strong&gt;daily logging habit&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s simple. It takes five minutes. And it pays back &lt;strong&gt;10x&lt;/strong&gt; in clarity, momentum, and output.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="why-im-recommending-daily-logs-to-every-developer-i-work-with">Why I&rsquo;m Recommending Daily Logs to Every Developer I Work With</h2>
<p>Most developers think productivity comes from better tooling, tighter sprint planning, or cutting meetings. Those help—but they don&rsquo;t solve the <em>real</em> problem:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You’re losing your own context, day after day.</p></blockquote>
<p>Start-of-day brain fog, half-solved bugs, forgotten edge cases… they all point to one thing: you didn’t close the loop yesterday.</p>
<p>That’s why I advise every dev I coach or lead to adopt a <strong>daily logging habit</strong>. It’s simple. It takes five minutes. And it pays back <strong>10x</strong> in clarity, momentum, and output.</p>
<p>This is a system you install once—and benefit from every week, forever.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-psychology-why-logging-works">The Psychology: Why Logging Works</h2>
<p>Developers often underestimate how much cognitive energy they waste trying to <em>remember where they left off</em>. Psychologists call this the <strong>Zeigarnik Effect</strong>—your brain holds onto unfinished tasks like open tabs in RAM.</p>
<p>Logging gives you closure. You offload the mess. Your brain goes, <em>&ldquo;Ah, good. That’s handled.&rdquo;</em></p>
<p>A 5-minute end-of-day log:</p>
<ul>
<li>Clears short-term memory</li>
<li>Builds continuity between sessions</li>
<li>Reduces cognitive switching costs</li>
<li>Increases problem-solving capacity</li>
<li>Improves next-day readiness</li>
</ul>
<p>It’s not just a journal. It’s a compression algorithm for your mental state.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="what-a-developer-log-looks-like">What a Developer Log Looks Like</h2>
<p>This isn’t journaling. You don’t need to be poetic or elaborate. Just structured, consistent, and useful to <em>future you</em> (or your teammates).</p>
<h3 id="simple-3-point-format">Simple 3-Point Format:</h3>
<p><strong>1. What I Did</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Finished login API (rate limiting added)</li>
<li>Fixed session bug (#231)</li>
<li>Debugged analytics memory leak</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>2. What’s Next</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Write tests for session manager</li>
<li>Refactor data pipeline (step 3)</li>
<li>Review frontend PR</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>3. What Broke or Was Weird</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Memory leak likely from 3rd-party SDK</li>
<li>AWS logs delayed by 5 mins</li>
<li>Auth intermittently returning 401s</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Optional Enhancers:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Productivity score (1–5)</li>
<li>Link to Jira ticket or Git branch</li>
<li>Quick insight: “Bug traced to cookie expiration, not Redis”</li>
</ul>
<p>This format builds a <strong>breadcrumb trail</strong> of your work. You’ll be stunned how often you refer back to it.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="tools-keep-it-stupid-simple">Tools: Keep It Stupid Simple</h2>
<p>The best tool is the one you’ll actually use—daily, without friction.</p>
<p>You could use something like <strong>Obsidian</strong>, which is excellent if you already have it set up for notes or knowledge management. It gives you powerful search, backlinks, daily templates, and local-first speed. It’s like having your own second brain that works perfectly for code-related journaling.</p>
<p>But honestly? What I do is even simpler:
I just keep a <code>daily-log.md</code> file inside my project folder and open it in VS Code at the end of the day. It’s fast, always available, and blends right into the development flow. I even have a small snippet that autofills the log template, so I don’t have to think about it.</p>
<p>Whichever route you choose, keep it local, lightweight, and searchable.</p>
<h3 id="-pro-tip-git--logs--magic">⚡ Pro Tip: Git + Logs = Magic</h3>
<p>Create a Git alias or hook that commits your daily log with your code. Now your log is versioned alongside your branches—instant traceability and context for every commit.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="real-world-win-debugging-faster">Real-World Win: Debugging Faster</h2>
<p>In a distributed system project, one engineer logged this:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Consumer lag spikes at 3pm UTC. Could be tied to deployment script.”</p></blockquote>
<p>They didn’t solve it that day—but another engineer picked it up the next morning, confirmed the hypothesis, and pushed a fix in under 30 minutes.</p>
<p>The log didn’t solve the bug.
It <strong>preserved the context</strong>—which solved the bug <em>faster</em>.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="build-the-habit">Build the Habit</h2>
<ul>
<li>Start small: Just do it for <em>yourself</em>, not the team.</li>
<li>Pick one place: Obsidian or a <code>daily-log.md</code>.</li>
<li>Make it part of your shutdown ritual.</li>
<li>Use a template so there’s no decision fatigue.</li>
<li>Reward yourself. You’re building a cognitive edge.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="wrap-up">Wrap Up</h2>
<p>Most productivity advice for devs focuses on planning the future. But your real power lies in <strong>closing your present</strong>.</p>
<p>Log your day.</p>
<p>Every log becomes a time capsule—of lessons learned, bugs spotted, patterns noticed, and momentum captured. Future you will thank you.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Five minutes a day. Ten times the clarity.
That’s leverage.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>How I Wrote Software 20 Years Ago (And Still Do)</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/05-20-25-how-i-write-software/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/05-20-25-how-i-write-software/</guid>
            <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A while back, I read about this process, from another developer, can’t even remember where, but it described a way of building software that felt oddly familiar. Almost like it had been plucked from my own memory, but written down with more structure and clarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That structure helped me refine the way I already worked. And now, even 20 years later, it’s still my go-to process whenever I’m starting something new. Whether I’m building a quick prototype, helping a client, or launching a new product — this method keeps me sane, clear, and productive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>A while back, I read about this process, from another developer, can’t even remember where, but it described a way of building software that felt oddly familiar. Almost like it had been plucked from my own memory, but written down with more structure and clarity.</p>
<p>That structure helped me refine the way I already worked. And now, even 20 years later, it’s still my go-to process whenever I’m starting something new. Whether I’m building a quick prototype, helping a client, or launching a new product — this method keeps me sane, clear, and productive.</p>
<p>It’s simple. Surprisingly simple. So simple you might think, “Well, duh.” But the truth is, most developers and teams still don’t do this. Not consistently. Not thoroughly. Not early enough.</p>
<p>Let me show you what I mean.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="dont-start-with-the-code">Don&rsquo;t Start with the Code</h2>
<p>Most people open their editor the moment an idea hits. I used to do that too. It feels good — like you&rsquo;re moving fast.</p>
<p>But often, you’re just rushing into a mess.</p>
<p>You start building screens before you know what data you’re working with. You guess at features instead of solving real problems. You paint the walls before laying the foundation.</p>
<p>Here’s what I do instead.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="step-1-what-who-and-how">Step 1: What, Who, and How</h2>
<p>Before anything else, I write — in plain, simple language — what I’m building, who it’s for, and how I expect people to use it.</p>
<p>No fancy frameworks. No personas. Just clarity.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;This is an app for freelance designers to track their projects. It&rsquo;s meant to help them stay organized, see deadlines at a glance, and feel less overwhelmed. I expect them to check it every morning and use it again in the evening.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>That’s already plenty.</p>
<p>Want to go deeper? Great. Add problems you&rsquo;re solving. Outline user pain points. But don’t overthink it. The point is to start with a real reason and a real person in mind.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="step-2-map-the-data">Step 2: Map the Data</h2>
<p>Once I know the “what” and the “who,” I move on to the data.</p>
<p>This is the part most people skip — but it’s one of the most valuable things you can do.</p>
<p>I ask:</p>
<ul>
<li>What are the main objects in this system?</li>
<li>How do they relate?</li>
<li>What actions can be taken on each?</li>
</ul>
<p>For example:</p>
<ul>
<li>A user creates projects</li>
<li>Projects have tasks</li>
<li>Tasks can be marked complete or given a due date</li>
<li>Tasks can belong to a category</li>
</ul>
<p>You don’t need to draw out the perfect schema. Just start sketching relationships. Think in terms of nouns and verbs. It gives your product structure, and makes everything else easier — especially when you&rsquo;re building fast.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="step-3-sketch-the-flow">Step 3: Sketch the Flow</h2>
<p>Next, I think about the screens.</p>
<ul>
<li>What’s the first screen users see?</li>
<li>Where can they go from there?</li>
<li>What actions happen on each page?</li>
</ul>
<p>Sometimes I’ll sketch this on paper. Sometimes I just jot down a list.</p>
<p>This part is about flow. It’s how your app feels in motion. The data model gives it bones. The flow gives it life.</p>
<p>You can go back and forth between steps 2 and 3. They inform each other. But together, they build the whole system before you touch a single line of code.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="step-4-choose-the-tech">Step 4: Choose the Tech</h2>
<p>Now that I know what I’m building, who it’s for, what data I need, and how the user moves through the product — now I choose my tools.</p>
<ul>
<li>What frontend makes sense?</li>
<li>What kind of backend do I need?</li>
<li>Is this mobile-first? Web-first?</li>
<li>Do I need real-time sync, or will a simple API do?</li>
</ul>
<p>At this point, the tech stack almost picks itself. There’s no guessing, no overengineering. You’re just filling in the gaps.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="step-5-build-it">Step 5: Build It</h2>
<p>This is the fun part — and now, it&rsquo;s actually <em>fun</em>, because I’m not wandering.</p>
<p>The product is already half-built in my mind and on paper. I just need to assemble it.</p>
<p>Coding becomes fast and focused. Design decisions are grounded in user needs and data. And best of all, I stay motivated because I know exactly what I’m trying to deliver and why.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="try-it-yourself">Try It Yourself</h2>
<p>You’re probably doing some of this already — maybe without realizing it. That’s great.</p>
<p>But I invite you to try doing it <em>on purpose</em>. Start your next project by writing out the “what, who, and how.” Map your data. Sketch your flow.</p>
<p>It doesn’t take long. In fact, it saves you time.</p>
<p>This method has helped me build faster, design better, and stay focused — for 20 years. It might just do the same for you.</p>
<p>Let me know if you try it.</p>
<p>– Jake</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>🌿 Seeking Non-Technical Cofounder – Wellness Meets Tech 🔬</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/05-18-25-looking-for-a-cofounder/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/05-18-25-looking-for-a-cofounder/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;🌿 Seeking Non-Technical Cofounder – Wellness Meets Tech 🔬&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m building a technological platform that blends medical testing with deep data analysis to deliver clear, actionable insights into personal wellness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our goal: simplify complex health data and help people take meaningful control of their well-being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m looking for a non-technical cofounder with a background in health, fitness, or wellness who can bring more than expertise — someone who contributes leadership, strategic vision, market insight, and fundraising acumen to help shape and scale a product that truly matters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>🌿 Seeking Non-Technical Cofounder – Wellness Meets Tech 🔬</p>
<p>I’m building a technological platform that blends medical testing with deep data analysis to deliver clear, actionable insights into personal wellness.</p>
<p>Our goal: simplify complex health data and help people take meaningful control of their well-being.</p>
<p>I’m looking for a non-technical cofounder with a background in health, fitness, or wellness who can bring more than expertise — someone who contributes leadership, strategic vision, market insight, and fundraising acumen to help shape and scale a product that truly matters.</p>
<p>💡 You might be:</p>
<p>A wellness or healthcare professional with business instincts</p>
<p>A former founder or advisor ready for a new mission</p>
<p>Deeply tuned into health trends, consumer behavior, and what’s next</p>
<p>Excited about turning vision into traction, and data into real-world impact</p>
<p>This is a cofounder-level opportunity — with equity, deep ownership, and creative freedom.</p>
<p>If this resonates with you — or you know someone who fits this energy — let’s connect. DMs are open.</p>
<p>#cofounder #wellnessstartup #healthtech #medicaltesting #technologicalplatform #foundersearch #preventivehealth #leadership #startupgrowth</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>How Do Augmented Developers Tackle the Complex Landscape of Modern Development?</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/09-19-23-why-is-now-the-perfect-time-for-the-rise-of-augmented-/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 10:58:41 -0500</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/09-19-23-why-is-now-the-perfect-time-for-the-rise-of-augmented-/</guid>
            <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Yukihiro Matsumoto, affectionately known as Matz, introduced the concept that a developer&amp;rsquo;s happiness is a pivotal aspect of development, it was a revelation. It emphasized that producing quality work isn&amp;rsquo;t just about the end product, but also about the journey and the well-being of those involved. This philosophy resonated deeply with me, reminding me of the Agile Manifesto&amp;rsquo;s pioneers who championed innovative ways to enhance work quality. Inspired by these trailblazers, I present &amp;ldquo;Augmented Developers&amp;rdquo; – my vision to elevate the quality of our work while ensuring the utmost satisfaction for everyone involved.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>When Yukihiro Matsumoto, affectionately known as Matz, introduced the concept that a developer&rsquo;s happiness is a pivotal aspect of development, it was a revelation. It emphasized that producing quality work isn&rsquo;t just about the end product, but also about the journey and the well-being of those involved. This philosophy resonated deeply with me, reminding me of the Agile Manifesto&rsquo;s pioneers who championed innovative ways to enhance work quality. Inspired by these trailblazers, I present &ldquo;Augmented Developers&rdquo; – my vision to elevate the quality of our work while ensuring the utmost satisfaction for everyone involved.</p>
<h2 id="current-landscape-of-software-development">Current landscape of software development</h2>
<p>Today&rsquo;s software development landscape is a maze of challenges:</p>
<ul>
<li>We navigate an increasingly intricate work environment.</li>
<li>Technologies evolve and complicate at a breakneck pace.</li>
<li>The platforms for delivery have diversified like never before.</li>
<li>While we have access to phenomenal tools, their sheer number can be overwhelming.</li>
<li>The demand for versatility in skills and expertise has skyrocketed.</li>
</ul>
<p>Amidst these challenges, we also grapple with:</p>
<ul>
<li>Clients whose expectations shift and sometimes remain ambiguous.</li>
<li>The daunting task of managing and updating legacy codebases.</li>
<li>Keeping up with the relentless speed of technological advancements.</li>
<li>Overcoming process inefficiencies and systemic breakdowns.</li>
<li>In this complex scenario, &ldquo;Augmented Developers&rdquo; aims to be the beacon, guiding us towards excellence and satisfaction in our craft.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="the-augmented-developer-a-new-breed-of-problem-solver">The Augmented Developer: A New Breed of Problem Solver</h2>
<p>In the ever-evolving realm of software development, a new archetype emerges: the &ldquo;Augmented Developer.&rdquo; Defined not just by their skills but by a unique blend of tools and a forward-thinking mindset, these developers stand a class apart. While traditional developers have laid the foundation, Augmented Developers build upon it, bringing innovation and adaptability to the forefront.</p>
<h2 id="strategies-for-navigating-client-expectations">Strategies for Navigating Client Expectations</h2>
<p>The Augmented Developer understands that at the heart of every project lies effective communication. By setting clear boundaries and expectations, they ensure a harmonious collaboration. They harness the power of prototyping, wireframing, and visualization tools, creating a shared vision with clients. Moreover, they play the role of educators, guiding clients through the maze of technology choices to arrive at solutions that are both optimal and future-proof.</p>
<h2 id="tackling-the-legacy-codebase-challenge">Tackling the Legacy Codebase Challenge</h2>
<p>We will just not do it&hellip; only greenfield projects to start as legacy is adding complexity for which we don&rsquo;t have good enough processes at the moment.</p>
<h2 id="simplifying-and-refactoring-ceremonies">Simplifying and refactoring ceremonies</h2>
<p>In the intricate ballet of software development, ceremonies play a pivotal role. However, not all ceremonies add value. As Augmented Developers, our primary objective is to foster meaningful communication with our clients. We strive to deeply understand their needs, aspirations, and challenges. This understanding is the bedrock upon which we build solutions.</p>
<p>But here&rsquo;s the catch: time is a finite resource. Every minute spent in redundant ceremonies is a minute taken away from crafting the right solutions. Moreover, unnecessary ceremonies don&rsquo;t just consume time; they also drain financial resources. In an industry where both time and budget are often tight, this is a luxury we cannot afford.</p>
<p>Therefore, we are on a mission to simplify and refactor our ceremonies. We are trimming the fat, eliminating processes that don&rsquo;t directly contribute to understanding our client&rsquo;s needs or delivering apt solutions. This streamlined approach ensures that every meeting, every discussion, and every collaboration is purpose-driven. It&rsquo;s not about doing more; it&rsquo;s about doing what&rsquo;s right. By focusing our energies on what truly matters, we are better positioned to deliver solutions that resonate, solutions that make a difference.</p>
<h2 id="in-the-end-it-is-a-ever-evolving-process">In the end, it is a ever evolving process</h2>
<p>Our journey in software development is akin to navigating the vast expanse of an ever-changing landscape. The processes we adhere to today are the culmination of our collective experiences, learnings, and reflections up to this point. They represent our best understanding of how to deliver exceptional value to our clients efficiently and effectively.</p>
<p>However, we recognize that the world of technology and client needs are in a state of constant flux. As we continue to undertake more projects and face new challenges, our perspectives will shift, and our strategies will adapt. This evolution is not just inevitable; it&rsquo;s embraced. We see it as an opportunity to refine our approach, to sharpen our methodologies, and to discover even better ways of working.</p>
<p>Our commitment is unwavering: to relentlessly pursue improvement. We are dedicated to enhancing our processes, not for the sake of change, but to find the optimal balance that serves both our team and our esteemed clients. We believe that by staying agile, receptive, and proactive, we can ensure that our processes remain as dynamic and innovative as the solutions we provide.</p>
<p>Having written all this, I have to add&hellip;</p>
<p>With joy,</p>
<p>Zhex</p>
<p>P.S. Make sure you visit <a href="https://augmented-devs.com/">https://augmented-devs.com/</a></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Modern Times Call for Modern Development</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/09-14-23-modern-times-call-for-modern-development/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 16:29:49 -0500</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/09-14-23-modern-times-call-for-modern-development/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Today we a launching Augmented Developers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://augmented-devs.com&#34;&gt;https://augmented-devs.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am doing it with joy and happiness. It should address number of issues I see with modern development and how developers are fitting into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://augmented-devs.com/assets/homepage/crypto_face@2700w.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked local data infused ChatGPT to help me write something knowing well about all the benefits we are offering, it is definitely kinder and nicer then I would ever be. Here is it&amp;rsquo;s take:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s rapidly evolving digital landscape, the demand for forward-thinking solutions is more pressing than ever. Traditional development methods, while reliable, often fall short in harnessing the full potential of modern technologies. This is where Augmented Developers come into the frame, offering a paradigm shift in the way we approach development. Here are some standout benefits of using Augmented Developers:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today we a launching Augmented Developers!</p>
<p><a href="https://augmented-devs.com">https://augmented-devs.com</a></p>
<p>I am doing it with joy and happiness. It should address number of issues I see with modern development and how developers are fitting into it.</p>
<p><img src="https://augmented-devs.com/assets/homepage/crypto_face@2700w.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p>I asked local data infused ChatGPT to help me write something knowing well about all the benefits we are offering, it is definitely kinder and nicer then I would ever be. Here is it&rsquo;s take:</p>
<p>In today&rsquo;s rapidly evolving digital landscape, the demand for forward-thinking solutions is more pressing than ever. Traditional development methods, while reliable, often fall short in harnessing the full potential of modern technologies. This is where Augmented Developers come into the frame, offering a paradigm shift in the way we approach development. Here are some standout benefits of using Augmented Developers:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Harnessing the Best Tools: Augmented Developers are always equipped with the latest tools and technologies. This not only ensures up-to-date solutions but also maximizes efficiency, security, and scalability.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Infusing Joy &amp; Creativity: In a field often perceived as cold and logical, Augmented Developers break the mold by introducing joy and happiness into the development process. This positive energy often translates to more innovative solutions and a brighter, more user-friendly end product.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Adaptable &amp; Future-Ready: The world of tech is always on the move. Augmented Developers are trained to anticipate and adapt to future trends, ensuring that the solutions they create today remain relevant tomorrow.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Holistic Development: Beyond just coding, Augmented Developers approach projects holistically. They consider user experience, market trends, and client visions, creating a comprehensive solution that addresses multiple facets of a challenge.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Efficient Problem Solving: Equipped with a vast array of modern tools and methodologies, Augmented Developers can quickly identify and rectify issues, ensuring smooth project progression and timely delivery.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Collaborative Spirit: Augmented Developers often thrive in collaborative environments. Their exposure to diverse tools and methods means they can communicate effectively with other team members, from designers to marketers, ensuring a cohesive final product.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>The digital age demands more than just developers; it calls for visionaries who can navigate the intricate web of modern technology with ease, creativity, and joy. Augmented Developers are the answer to this call, representing the gold standard in contemporary development. In a world where technology is ever-advancing, isn&rsquo;t it time we advance our developers too?</p>
<hr>
<p>Remember, Augmented Developers is what you need to develop solutions for modern business.</p>
<p><a href="https://augmented-devs.com">https://augmented-devs.com</a></p>
<p>Sincerely with joy,</p>
<p>Zhex</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Groundhog Day</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/04-03-23-groundhog-day/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 14:25:55 -0500</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/04-03-23-groundhog-day/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Imagine being trapped in a never-ending cycle where each day is a repetition of the previous one, with little to no change. This is the premise of the classic comedy-drama film &amp;ldquo;Groundhog Day,&amp;rdquo; in which the protagonist, Phil Connors, finds himself living the same day over and over again. While the movie is a work of fiction, it serves as a compelling metaphor for the experiences of individuals with ADHD, particularly those who work as programmers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Imagine being trapped in a never-ending cycle where each day is a repetition of the previous one, with little to no change. This is the premise of the classic comedy-drama film &ldquo;Groundhog Day,&rdquo; in which the protagonist, Phil Connors, finds himself living the same day over and over again. While the movie is a work of fiction, it serves as a compelling metaphor for the experiences of individuals with ADHD, particularly those who work as programmers.</p>
<p>For me as a programmer, daily life can feel like a perpetual Groundhog Day. There are things and projects I would like to accomplish, which I am trying really hard to work on and focus. Then weeks, months and sometimes year later, I would find notes on the projects I wanted to do then&hellip; and it is the same projects and things I am trying to do now. And when this happens this is just soul-crushing.</p>
<p>ADHD is characterized by difficulty in sustaining attention, impulsivity, and hyperactivity. These symptoms can manifest in various ways, but for programmers, they may lead to struggles with time management, task completion, and organization.</p>
<p>Just as Phil Connors is unable to escape the cycle of February 2nd, programmers with ADHD may find themselves stuck in a loop of unfinished projects and missed deadlines. The fast-paced, detail-oriented nature of coding can be overwhelming for those who struggle to maintain focus. Additionally, the constant demand for multitasking and the need to switch between different tasks can exacerbate the symptoms of ADHD.</p>
<p>Scrum methodology with endless meetings definitely doesn&rsquo;t help and is especially difficult for people like me. And people like me&hellip; there is a lot of my colleagues who are like me, it seems that programming attracts people like me and our messed up brains are especially good at programming.</p>
<p>I am in constant search of new organizational methods and ways how I can sustain my focus so I can make what I always wanted to make.</p>
<p>Other people say there are advantages to have a mind like I do (definitely agree) in terms of creativity, ideas, enthysiasm that you can produce. I definitely wouldn&rsquo;t want to lose any of that, but it is really hard when you realize you were &ldquo;looping&rdquo; for months and years over something really simple.</p>
<p>Breaking the loop of Groundhog Day requires a combination of self-awareness, support, and strategies. Here is what I found elsewhere suggested and I am trying to apply:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Structure Your Day: Create a daily routine with clear priorities and set achievable goals. Utilize time management tools, such as timers or scheduling apps, to stay on track.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Minimize Distractions: Designate a workspace free of distractions, and use noise-cancelling headphones or white noise machines to block out external sounds.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Take Regular Breaks: Allow yourself regular breaks to recharge and regain focus. Practice mindfulness techniques or engage in physical activity to reduce stress. Walks outside help a lot.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Leverage Your Strengths: Embrace your creativity and problem-solving skills. Identify tasks that align with your strengths and interests.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Seek Support: Connect with others who have similar experiences, talk to your colleagues who struggle like you, it will help immensely knowing others have similar problems.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Listening to ambient music really helps a lot.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Like in the movie, you have to break the loop, do the work, make the Win. It happens, but it requires a lot of energy and often people don&rsquo;t understand how much emotional energy it takes to accomplish some simple things that they take for granted.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Ai and Creativity 2nd part</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/03-22-24-ai-and-creativity-2/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/03-22-24-ai-and-creativity-2/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to further expand on previous article and worked with ChatGPT to explore few more points of interest when it comes to creativity and how AI can help us expand it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**Introduction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As previously discussed, AI is not only emulating human creativity but also stimulating and enhancing it. By delving deeper into the ways AI can boost and augment the human creative process, we can better understand the potential of this groundbreaking partnership. In this article, we will explore the various ways AI is revolutionizing creativity and idea generation, paving the way for unprecedented innovation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I wanted to further expand on previous article and worked with ChatGPT to explore few more points of interest when it comes to creativity and how AI can help us expand it.</p>
<p>**Introduction</p>
<p>As previously discussed, AI is not only emulating human creativity but also stimulating and enhancing it. By delving deeper into the ways AI can boost and augment the human creative process, we can better understand the potential of this groundbreaking partnership. In this article, we will explore the various ways AI is revolutionizing creativity and idea generation, paving the way for unprecedented innovation.</p>
<ol start="6">
<li>Customizing Creative Inspiration</li>
</ol>
<p>AI algorithms can curate personalized inspiration feeds based on an individual&rsquo;s interests, preferences, and creative goals. By presenting a diverse range of ideas, images, and content tailored to the user, AI helps stimulate the creative process and encourages individuals to think outside the box. This continuous flow of inspiration can lead to the development of groundbreaking ideas and creative solutions.</p>
<ol start="7">
<li>Real-time Creative Feedback</li>
</ol>
<p>AI systems can provide real-time feedback on creative work, enabling individuals to make adjustments and refinements as they go. By offering objective analysis and suggestions for improvement, AI helps creators fine-tune their ideas and achieve the desired outcome more efficiently. This continuous feedback loop encourages experimentation and growth, allowing individuals to refine their creative skills over time.</p>
<ol start="8">
<li>Analyzing and Predicting Creative Trends</li>
</ol>
<p>One of the most significant advantages of AI in the creative realm is its ability to analyze vast amounts of data and predict emerging trends. By identifying patterns and trends in consumer preferences, social media, and other creative fields, AI can provide insights into the future direction of creative industries. This knowledge enables creators to stay ahead of the curve and develop ideas that resonate with their target audience.</p>
<ol start="9">
<li>Encouraging Cross-disciplinary Creativity</li>
</ol>
<p>AI can serve as a bridge between different creative disciplines, fostering collaboration and idea exchange among professionals from various fields. By analyzing and identifying common threads and themes across disciplines, AI can suggest innovative ways to combine different techniques, styles, and approaches. This cross-disciplinary creativity encourages individuals to think beyond their own expertise, leading to the development of unique and groundbreaking ideas.</p>
<ol start="10">
<li>Democratising Creativity</li>
</ol>
<p>AI-powered tools are becoming more accessible, enabling individuals with varying levels of skill and expertise to engage in the creative process. By providing easy-to-use interfaces and automating complex tasks, AI is democratizing creativity, allowing more people to explore their creative potential. This widespread access to creative tools and resources is likely to result in a surge of new ideas and innovations.</p>
<ol start="11">
<li>Overcoming Creative Bias</li>
</ol>
<p>Human creativity can sometimes be influenced by personal biases, leading to the development of ideas that cater to specific tastes and preferences. AI, on the other hand, can provide an objective perspective by analyzing data from various sources and offering unbiased suggestions. This objectivity helps creators challenge their assumptions and develop ideas that appeal to a broader audience.</p>
<p>Conclusion</p>
<p>AI is playing an increasingly vital role in augmenting and boosting human creativity. By customizing creative inspiration, providing real-time feedback, analyzing and predicting trends, encouraging cross-disciplinary collaboration, democratizing creativity, and overcoming creative biases, AI is revolutionizing the way we approach and experience the creative process. As AI and human intelligence continue to work in tandem, we can anticipate a future filled with innovative ideas and groundbreaking solutions that enrich our world and push the boundaries of what we once thought possible.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Ai And Creativity</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/03-23-23-ai-and-creativity/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/03-23-23-ai-and-creativity/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;I believe that AI can significantly aid and boost human creativity and enhance collaboration. This is something that has to be proven just yet, but I want to explore it and see where we can use AI for that purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article and it&amp;rsquo;s points were made using ChatGPT-4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creativity is often considered the exclusive domain of human intelligence. However, with the advancement of artificial intelligence (AI), it has become evident that AI can not only emulate human creativity but can also stimulate and enhance it. This article explores how AI is transforming the way we approach creative thinking and ideas, and how this innovative partnership between AI and humans can lead to unparalleled innovation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I believe that AI can significantly aid and boost human creativity and enhance collaboration. This is something that has to be proven just yet, but I want to explore it and see where we can use AI for that purpose.</p>
<p>This article and it&rsquo;s points were made using ChatGPT-4.</p>
<h4 id="introduction">Introduction</h4>
<p>Creativity is often considered the exclusive domain of human intelligence. However, with the advancement of artificial intelligence (AI), it has become evident that AI can not only emulate human creativity but can also stimulate and enhance it. This article explores how AI is transforming the way we approach creative thinking and ideas, and how this innovative partnership between AI and humans can lead to unparalleled innovation.</p>
<ol>
<li>AI as a Creative Assistant</li>
</ol>
<p>AI-powered tools and algorithms can now act as creative assistants, helping individuals brainstorm, ideate, and experiment with new concepts. These tools can analyze vast amounts of data, recognize patterns, and generate novel suggestions based on the user&rsquo;s inputs. By providing unique and relevant ideas, AI helps creators overcome creative blocks and come up with innovative solutions to complex problems.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li>Expanding the Creative Playground</li>
</ol>
<p>When it comes to creativity, exposure to diverse perspectives is crucial. AI can analyze and learn from a multitude of sources, creating new connections and ideas that might not have been considered otherwise. By exposing humans to a broader range of influences, AI empowers them to think beyond the boundaries of their own experiences and explore uncharted creative territories.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li>Enhancing Collaboration</li>
</ol>
<p>AI can facilitate collaboration among creative professionals by providing a common platform for idea sharing, organization, and development. By leveraging machine learning algorithms, AI can identify the strengths of individual collaborators and suggest how their skills can be best utilized in a project. This enhances teamwork and ensures that the creative process is optimized for the best results.</p>
<ol start="4">
<li>Personalized Creativity Coaching</li>
</ol>
<p>One of the most exciting ways AI can stimulate human creativity is through personalized coaching. AI can analyze an individual&rsquo;s creative habits, preferences, and strengths, and provide tailored recommendations and exercises to help them improve. This personalized approach allows individuals to develop their creativity in ways that are most effective for them, rather than following a one-size-fits-all model.</p>
<ol start="5">
<li>Accelerating the Creative Process</li>
</ol>
<p>AI can help streamline the creative process by automating repetitive tasks and providing real-time feedback. This allows creators to focus on the essence of their work and iterate more quickly. As AI continues to evolve, it will become increasingly adept at understanding and evaluating creative output, further accelerating the ideation and refinement process.</p>
<p>Conclusion</p>
<p>As AI continues to advance, its ability to stimulate creativity and ideas among humans will only grow stronger. By acting as a creative assistant, expanding the creative playground, enhancing collaboration, providing personalized coaching, and accelerating the creative process, AI is revolutionizing the way humans approach and experience creativity. In this symbiotic relationship, AI and human intelligence work together to unlock new levels of innovation, enriching our world with novel ideas and groundbreaking solutions.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Benefits of Remote Work</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/03-21-23-benefits-of-remote-work/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/03-21-23-benefits-of-remote-work/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;As the world has shifted toward remote work, I have witnessed firsthand the numerous advantages it offers to both employees and employers. Working from home has allowed me to save time on my daily commute, become more productive and focused, and enjoy increased flexibility as a parent. Not only that, remote work has proven to be environmentally friendly and has required the development of innovative management strategies for success. In this article, I will share my experience with these benefits, as well as other advantages that have made remote work an invaluable option for me and many others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As the world has shifted toward remote work, I have witnessed firsthand the numerous advantages it offers to both employees and employers. Working from home has allowed me to save time on my daily commute, become more productive and focused, and enjoy increased flexibility as a parent. Not only that, remote work has proven to be environmentally friendly and has required the development of innovative management strategies for success. In this article, I will share my experience with these benefits, as well as other advantages that have made remote work an invaluable option for me and many others.</p>
<h3 id="changes-cause-pushback">Changes cause pushback</h3>
<p>Quite a number of managers, especially middle managers and CEOs are feeling lost and confused by these changes. On one hand they have all this savings and flexibility because they have a lot of fixed cost of owning real-estate and maintaining offices just gone. On the other hand,they feel the need to control people and they are not sure how to go about it.</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s look at the benefits of remote work.</p>
<h3 id="saving-time">Saving Time</h3>
<p>One of the most significant benefits of remote work is the considerable amount of time I&rsquo;ve saved by eliminating my daily commute. I can now use this time for more valuable activities, such as spending time with my family, pursuing hobbies, or focusing on personal health and well-being.</p>
<h3 id="increased-productivity-and-focus">Increased Productivity and Focus</h3>
<p>Working remotely has allowed me to create my ideal work environment, leading to increased productivity and focus. By minimizing distractions typically found in traditional office settings, I find that I can concentrate better on my tasks, resulting in a higher quality of work and more efficient output.</p>
<h3 id="flexibility-for-parents">Flexibility for Parents</h3>
<p>As a parent, remote work has been a game-changer, offering more time to spend with my children and the ability to balance work and family life better. This flexibility has significantly reduced the stress associated with juggling professional and personal responsibilities, ultimately leading to a happier, healthier work-life balance.</p>
<h3 id="innovative-management-strategies">Innovative Management Strategies</h3>
<p>The shift to remote work has necessitated the development of new ways to manage teams and projects. By embracing remote work, I&rsquo;ve been able to foster a culture of trust and accountability within my team, empowering my colleagues to take ownership of their tasks. As a manager, I&rsquo;ve had to develop effective communication and collaboration strategies to ensure my remote team remains engaged and aligned with company goals. This has led to more innovative and efficient management practices that benefit both my colleagues and the organization.</p>
<h3 id="environmental-benefits">Environmental Benefits</h3>
<p>Working remotely is an eco-friendly choice for me and my employer. By reducing the number of vehicles on the road, remote work can significantly decrease greenhouse gas emissions and air pollution. Additionally, my employer can lower their energy consumption by requiring less office space and resources, thereby minimizing their overall environmental impact.</p>
<h3 id="access-to-a-global-talent-pool">Access to a Global Talent Pool</h3>
<p>Remote work has allowed my employer to tap into a global talent pool, enabling them to hire the best and brightest candidates regardless of their geographical location. This expanded access to talent has led to greater diversity and a more skilled workforce, driving innovation and growth within the company.</p>
<h3 id="employee-retention-and-satisfaction">Employee Retention and Satisfaction</h3>
<p>My company&rsquo;s remote work policy has significantly boosted my satisfaction as an employee, increasing the likelihood that I&rsquo;ll stay with the organization. Employees who enjoy the benefits of remote work are more likely to remain with their current employer, reducing the time and cost associated with turnover.</p>
<h3 id="cost-savings-for-businesses">Cost Savings for Businesses</h3>
<p>Remote work can result in significant cost savings for businesses. By reducing the need for office space, companies can lower their overhead expenses, such as rent, utilities, and office supplies. Additionally, remote work can lead to decreased employee absenteeism, as employees can continue working even when they are unwell or facing personal challenges.</p>
<h3 id="in-the-end">In the end</h3>
<p>My experience with remote work has been overwhelmingly positive, offering a multitude of benefits like time savings, increased productivity, enhanced flexibility, and environmental sustainability. As remote work continues to gain traction, it is crucial for organizations to adapt and embrace the new ways of managing remote teams to ensure success in this ever-evolving landscape. By leveraging these benefits, companies can foster a more engaged, productive, and satisfied workforce while contributing to a greener, more sustainable future.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Year of Creative Experiments</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/03-19-23-year-of-creative-experiments/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/03-19-23-year-of-creative-experiments/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;I am part of the NessLabs community and recently a member of NessLabs, a lovely women presented a topic of a whole year of creative experiments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Idea is to always have some small projects to work on, that will be limited in scope and will bring you joy and happiness of exploring new areas in your life or expanding existing ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It works like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a list of experiments you would like to do&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You would pick a single experiment every month.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They also need to be small and easily achievable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experiment has to be defined clearly with outcome and goal that you want to accomplish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You create a list of 12 things you will do throughout the year. Assign every experiment to month and start. And if you change your mind along the way, it is fine, replace, remove, add. But once you start working on something, do it till completion. Or at least try to finish it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am part of the NessLabs community and recently a member of NessLabs, a lovely women presented a topic of a whole year of creative experiments.</p>
<p>Idea is to always have some small projects to work on, that will be limited in scope and will bring you joy and happiness of exploring new areas in your life or expanding existing ones.</p>
<p>It works like this:</p>
<ul>
<li>Make a list of experiments you would like to do</li>
<li>You would pick a single experiment every month.</li>
<li>They also need to be small and easily achievable</li>
<li>Experiment has to be defined clearly with outcome and goal that you want to accomplish</li>
</ul>
<p>You create a list of 12 things you will do throughout the year. Assign every experiment to month and start. And if you change your mind along the way, it is fine, replace, remove, add. But once you start working on something, do it till completion. Or at least try to finish it.</p>
<p>And if you fail in some, so what. There is always next month and another experiment waiting for you.</p>
<p>They just have to be small enough to be done in a month.</p>
<h3 id="my-modifications">My modifications</h3>
<p>I wanted to tweak this a little bit.</p>
<p>First I created a list of experiments that I would like to do.
Not all are good to work in a month. So I decided to size them:
S - small - 2 weeks
M - medium - 4 weeks ie. a month
L - large - 6 weeks (more like Jason Friend sprint)</p>
<p>One of the first is to write to blog just 3 posts and 15 microposts.
This is for end of March goal.</p>
<p>Before that I re-created and re-thought image of Dakic OnLine. That turned out to be way more fun then I expected it to be. I thought I will just rethink who are customers are and how we want to serve them. In the end, I realized that what would make me happy is to be a force of good in this world and re-thought the whole mission.
There is a blog post about it.</p>
<p>I already wrote about Remote Work. I have 2 part article about AI almost done.
I would like to write about experience of having ADHD.
I have some thoughts about modern management and planning, I will start writing about it and we will see if this makes sense or not.</p>
<p>So, I am already half way through my second experiment and it is fun and I am enjoying.</p>
<p>People are wired to create and this lets you make more and easier.</p>
<p>So this is my experience, maybe I can inspire you to also do this?</p>
<p>Here is original article:
<a href="https://www.charlottegrysolle.com/creative-experiments/">https://www.charlottegrysolle.com/creative-experiments/</a></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Dakic Online Ai Makes Song</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/03-14-23-dakic-online-ai-makes-song/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 23:11:52 -0500</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/03-14-23-dakic-online-ai-makes-song/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;I asked ChatGPT-3.5 to make a song about our mission to make a world a better place,
here is what it came up with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Innovation and technology,&lt;br&gt;
They make our lives so bright,&lt;br&gt;
They bring us all together,&lt;br&gt;
And help us see the light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dakic OnLine, the name we know,&lt;br&gt;
The company with a vision,&lt;br&gt;
To make our world a better place,&lt;br&gt;
With endless innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through software, through devices,&lt;br&gt;
Through all the things we see,&lt;br&gt;
Dakic OnLine brings us closer,&lt;br&gt;
To the world we want to be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I asked ChatGPT-3.5 to make a song about our mission to make a world a better place,
here is what it came up with:</p>
<p>Innovation and technology,<br>
They make our lives so bright,<br>
They bring us all together,<br>
And help us see the light.</p>
<p>Dakic OnLine, the name we know,<br>
The company with a vision,<br>
To make our world a better place,<br>
With endless innovation.</p>
<p>Through software, through devices,<br>
Through all the things we see,<br>
Dakic OnLine brings us closer,<br>
To the world we want to be.</p>
<p>Making people&rsquo;s lives better,<br>
Is what this company strives for,<br>
With every new creation,<br>
They open up new doors.</p>
<p>So let us all applaud them,<br>
For the work they do each day,<br>
For bringing us a brighter world,<br>
And showing us the way.</p>
<p>P.S. Version 4 did better but it is longer and more cerebral song, yet this one is simpler and more readable in my view.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Making World a Better Place</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/03-14-23-making-world-a-better-place/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 15:02:10 -0500</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/03-14-23-making-world-a-better-place/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is about my values that I defined long time ago and some tweaks I want to add as I think things through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is long and rambly post, you can find conclusion near the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-the-past&#34;&gt;In the past&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a very long time mission of Dakic OnLine was to &amp;ldquo;create better business online using innovation&amp;rdquo; or specifically&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Creating Better Business in Economy of Ideas&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried my best to uphold those values, mostly by trying to offer innovative solutions and using latest technology to give our clients an edge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This post is about my values that I defined long time ago and some tweaks I want to add as I think things through.</p>
<p>It is long and rambly post, you can find conclusion near the end.</p>
<h3 id="in-the-past">In the past</h3>
<p>For a very long time mission of Dakic OnLine was to &ldquo;create better business online using innovation&rdquo; or specifically</p>
<p>&ldquo;Creating Better Business in Economy of Ideas&rdquo;</p>
<p>I tried my best to uphold those values, mostly by trying to offer innovative solutions and using latest technology to give our clients an edge.</p>
<p>In some other way, I failed to do some really more substantial impact on business climate and innovation.</p>
<p>Few times we were close, PersistentPenny and Zelio were really good ways to support smaller businesses but I didn&rsquo;t follow through to fully make them reality.</p>
<p>Yes I was on top of technology, businesses got to use Rails even before it was cool. Stakeholders were laughing at using methodology Extreme Programming and Agile. Along the way there were some interesting solutions that allowed people to break grounds that they would not otherwise.</p>
<p>We also spearheaded PWAs, a Progressive WebApps, an alternative to mobile app development. So instead of building web app, IOS and Android, huge hassle with appstores etc. you just build a single responsive app that has most of features as mobile apps, and if it gets traction, we can then develop native apps.</p>
<p>I think this last one saved one startup a ton of money. It still didn&rsquo;t help them in the end because their problem was never software.</p>
<p>I also made sure that people who work for us are treated nicely and paid well and on time, even if we were not.</p>
<p>So that is how I worked in the past.</p>
<h3 id="how-good-were-we">How good were we?</h3>
<p>There is nothing wrong with this approach.</p>
<p>One thing that was always bothering me, we didn&rsquo;t create any products that made small businesses and others genuinely work better and get some insane value from us. There were some products for marketing we did but kind of didn&rsquo;t really went all in with those, but that is as close to creating something that would genuinely improve business online, which was my goal.</p>
<p>My goal was to use innovation and technlogy to improve doing business online.</p>
<p>By my own measures, this failed, I just don&rsquo;t feel I accomplished what I wanted to do.</p>
<p>Few times we were really close to do just that but somehow we didn&rsquo;t, things fizzled out.</p>
<h3 id="what-didnt-work">What didn&rsquo;t work</h3>
<p>I don&rsquo;t think innovation how I imagined it worked or maybe it was just how implemented it.</p>
<p>I had methodology which would create wires, prototype, high figelity mvp, then mvp.</p>
<p>I had really hard time getting clients to finance this even though it was in their interest not to waste money on development they ultimately don&rsquo;t need. They were just wasting money and then scrambled when they are short on funds to cut features or future work.</p>
<h3 id="what-do-i-want-to-do-now">What do I want to do now</h3>
<p>I had recently talked with EvilInsuranceCorp (not their real name) to work for them. I saw this as opportunity to improve on experience patients have when are reviewing coverage and how their payments are going through. That didn&rsquo;t go through and  it was for the better.</p>
<p>I read article today that they have AI alghoritm to deny coverage to people based on some profit factors, not really if patient needs that coverage. There was sad story of elderly people being denied coverage and using all their hard earned savings to cover for life saving treatment.</p>
<p>Not really &lsquo;A Force For Good&rsquo; like I want to see myself.</p>
<p>This got me thinking. This &ldquo;Better Business OnLine&rdquo; didn&rsquo;t really work for a long time already, nor it made me happy.</p>
<p>What I really always wanted is to be &ldquo;A Force For Good&rdquo;, even if this drove some people crazy.</p>
<p>So I thought about what I really like and how I want to work. I came up with following mission and have some idea how to go about it.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Making People Lives Better Through Innovation And Technology&rdquo;</p>
<p>From businesses, I would like to focus on individual people and work on what makes their lives better and how I can improve their experience of living.</p>
<p>This can be a startup founder, but it can be a consumer as well.</p>
<p>I thought about doing something for developers, but&hellip; that is tricky and I never wanted to be just focused on developers.</p>
<p>So I will be focused on individual happines and accomplishment first.</p>
<p>I think my focus on businesses was mostly influenced by people online who said it is hard to do consumer apps and there is way more value to be provided for small and medium business.</p>
<p>I want to work with people first. Maybe this is influence of me doing Design Systems and Design Thinking, to be so people focused, but I think I always was interested in how people are using software I was involved in making.</p>
<h3 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>
<p>From now on:</p>
<p><strong>&ldquo;Making People Lives Better Through Innovation And Technology&rdquo;</strong></p>
<p>it might sound mundane but it is what I genuinely want to do.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
